Chebesi EdyLionel Awah

Full Stack Software Developer

Douala chebesiawah@gmail.com 237677972126

I am a Self taught freelance developer who learned how to build high performance web and mobile apps by watching videos on Udemy and YouTube since 2019. Over the past two years, I have ameliorated my skills while working on diverse projects from clients across different parts of the world. I am specialized in projects using MERN stack, because I just love MERN.

- I am a good team worker,
- Attentive to details,
- Ouick to learn.
- And I love challenges

I love sports, particularly football, am interested in world politics, dancing and taking walks.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

Work Experience

Front End Developer

Virtual Pro Gaming - Mason, OH September 2021 to November 2021

I worked on a project that used React Js and Typescript. Using React Query, I had to interact with the server, getting data from the back and displaying it on the client side. I also updated the User Interface of the client side using libraries like Materia UI.

Full Stack Developer

BEWOCA NGO - Bamenda January 2021 to February 2021

I built and managed their Web application for the NGO using React, Node and MSQL.

Front End Web Developer

Silver Line Startup - Douala January 2020 to December 2020

Developed User Interfaces using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and React Js . I also had tasks that involved fetching data from the server using APIs. Aided the team in updating company's website as well as redesigned user experience for websites

Education

Diploma in Web Development

Udemy

January 2019 to December 2019

Bachelor's degree in Law and Public Administration

University of Yaounde 2 Soa - Yaounde

October 2011 to August 2014

Skills

- HTML5
- MongoDB
- TypeScript
- Bootstrap
- Vue.js
- React Native
- Express.js
- MySQL
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Node.js
- React js
- Firebase
- Material UI

Languages

- English Fluent
- French Intermediate
- Spanish Beginner

Links

https://chebsportfolio.netlify.app/

https://github.com/MeryAmun

https://www.linkedin.com/in/chebesi-awah-b891331ab/